Trouble sleeping?
睡不着么？
Arm's acting up
麒麟臂发作了
Ah, of course
啊，难怪了
So logically you got out of bed, dressed yourself completely
所以你就理所当然地起床，穿得整整齐齐
and decided to gaze menacingly out into the distance
然后决定用杀人的目光眺望远方
What's wrong?
到底怎么了？
I've trusted him for years, we both have
我们俩都信任他这么多年了
I just..
我只是..
I can't help but feel..like he's keeping us in the dark
不禁隐隐感觉..他有什么瞒着我们
Don't be ridiculous!
别乱脑补了
You know very well that we are not the ones in the dark
你明明知道我们不是被瞒着的人
That makes it worse
那就更糟了
I refuse to believe that a man I've trusted for so long..
我拒绝相信一个我信任了这么久的人..
would act so..
会表现得如此..
passively
被动
You're a good person, James
你是个好人，James
You've always done what you think is best for the people
你从来都做着自认最符合民众利益的事
Even against strong protest
即使遭到强烈反对
It's admirable
令人钦佩
But it's high time you stopped talking about trust and started showing it
但现在是时候把你挂在嘴边的信任付诸行动了
Ozpin has experience that the rest of us lack
Ozpin的经验比我们其他人丰富
And I think that's something worth remembering
我觉得这点需要牢记
Blake, are you awake?
Blake，还醒着么？
Yeah
嗯
Why do you think he asked us about being a Huntress?
你觉得他为什么要问我们当猎人的理由？
Like..what was he trying to say?
他..到底想说什么？
Maybe he was just curious
可能他只是好奇
You think?
你这么想？
No
不
Weiss, are you awake?
Weiss，醒着么？
Of course I'm awake! You two are talking
当然醒着啊！你们俩在说话嘛
And I think he..
我觉得他..
When I said I wanted to honor my family's name, I meant it, but..
当我说我要光宗耀祖时，我是认真的，但..
It's not what you think
不是你们想的那样
I'm not stupid, I'm fully aware of what my father has done with the Schnee Dust Company
我可不傻，我完全清楚我老爹如何发展雪倪尘晶公司的
Since he took control, our business has operated in a..
他在公司掌权以后，我们的生意就处于..
moral grey area
道德的灰色地带了
That's putting it lightly
真是轻描淡写
Which is why I feel the needs to make things right
所以我才觉得有必要纠正
If I'd taken a job in Atlas, it wouldn't have changed anything
如果我在阿特拉斯工作，什么都改变不了
My father was not the start of our name, and I refuse to let him be the end of it
我老爹不是雪倪家的创始人，我也不会让他葬送整个家族
All my life, I fought for what I thought was right
我这一生都在为自己的信念奋斗
I had a partner named Adam
我曾经有个同伴叫Adam
More of a mentor, actually
其实更像个导师
He always assured me that what we were doing would make the world a better place
他经常向我保证我们的所作所为能让世界变得更美好
But of course, his idea of a perfect future turned out to be..
不过当然了，他脑海里的美好未来其实..
not perfect for everyone
只对部分人美好
I joined the Academy
我进了学院
because I knew Huntsmen and Huntresses were regarded as the most noble warriors in the world
因为我知道猎人被看成这个世上最崇高的战士
Always fighting for good
永远为正义而战
But I never really thought past that
但我从未真正地深入思考
When I leave the Academy..
当我离开学院时..
What will I..
我要怎么..
How can I undo so many years of hate?
我该如何消除多年的仇恨？
I'm sure you'd figure it out
你肯定能有办法的
You're not one to back down from a challenge, Blake
你可不是一个回避挑战的人，Blake
But I am!
可我就是啊！
I do it all the time
我一直都这样啊
When you learned I was a Faunus, I didn't know what to do, so I ran
当你们知道我是弗纳人时，我不知所措，就跑了
When I realized my oldest partner had become a monster, I ran
当我认识到我最初的搭档变成了怪物，我跑了
Even my Semblance..
甚至连我的外像力..
I was born with the ability to leave behind a shadow of myself
我天生就有在身后留下残影的能力
an empty copy that takes the hit while I run away
在一个影子替我承受攻击时趁机逃跑
At least you two have something that drives you
至少你们俩有目标有动力
I've just kinda of always, gone with the flow, you know
我从来只是顺其自然、随波逐流
And that's fine, I mean, that's who I am
当然这也挺好，我本来就这样
But how long can I really do that for?
但我能这样保持多久？
I wanna be a Huntress
我想成为猎人
not really because I wanna be a hero
并不是因为想做英雄
but because I want the adventure
只是因为想冒险
I want a life where I won't know what tomorrow will bring
我想要一种“今日不知明日事”的生活
And that'll be a good thing
这就很好了
Being a Huntress just happens to line up with that
成为猎人只是碰巧与我的目的一致
I'm not like Ruby
我不像Ruby
She's always wanted to be a Huntress
她一直想成为猎人
It's like she said
就像她说的
Ever since she was a kid, she'd judged about being the heroes in the books
她从小时候就决定要成为书中的英雄了
Helping people and saving the day, and never asking for anything else in return
助人为乐，拯救世界，而且从不要求任何回报
Even when she couldn't fight, she knew that's what she wanted to do
即使那时还无法战斗，她已经明确了这个目标
That's why she trained so hard to get where she is today
所以她努力训练达到今天这种程度
Well, she's still just a kid
嘛，她依然只是个孩子
She's only two years younger, we're all kids
她只比我们小两岁，我们都是孩子
Well, not anymore
不再算孩子了
I mean, look where we are
我是说，看看我们在哪儿
In the middle of a warzone and armed to the teeth
处于战争地带的中心，全副武装
It's the life we chose
这是我们选择的生活
It's a job
这是个工作
We all had this romanticized vision of being a Huntress in our heads
我们都脑补过猎人这个职业浪漫的一面
But at the end of the day
但归根结底
It's a job to protect the people
这是个守护人民的工作
And whatever we want, will have to come seconds
我们自己想要的永远排在第二位
Ah -v-?
啊-v-？
Zwei, it's late, go back to bed
Zwei，很晚了，快睡觉嘛
Zwei, Zwei!
Zwei，Zwei！
Ugh~
唉~
Zwei
Zwei
Zwei, where are you?
Zwei，你在哪儿？
Zwei~
Zwei~
Uh?
哈？
Zwei, this is a wasteland, you literally could've done that anywhere
Zwei，这是片废墟，你在哪儿都能解决的
What was that?
那是什么？
What was what?
什么是什么？
I thought I heard a Beowolf or something
我好像听到了贝奥狼什么的
Ughn, let's just finish our patrol and get back to base
哎呀，快巡逻结束回基地吧
This place gives me the creeps
这地方让我毛骨悚然
Did they go in yet?
他们进去了吗？
One bark means yes
进去了就汪一下
Oh! This is it, this is it!
噢！就是这里了！
Aw man!
信号 -- 低
Come on, we gotta get the others
来，我们得找其他人来
Huh?
咦？
Freeze!
别动！
Where did she come from?
她哪儿冒出来的？
You're a long way from home, little girl
这不是你该来的地方，小女孩
Hey, hands off!
喂，给我放手！
The boss is gonna want to see this one
老大会想看看这个的
Hey Weiss, it's your..
Weiss呀，到你..
Ruby?
Ruby？
Hey, where's Ruby?
话说，Ruby呢？
What?
啥？
Zwei?
Zwei？
What's going on?
发生什么了？
Grab your weapons
拿好武器
Your leader may be in trouble
你们队长可能有麻烦了
Give me a hand, I can't fix it
帮我一下，这个弄不好
Hey, be careful!
喂，小心点！
What are you trying to do, blow us to the moon?
你想干吗，把我们炸上月球？
Sorry sir!
抱歉长官！
Hey boss!
老大！
Found something you might wanna see!
找到了你可能想看的东西
Is it good or bad, Perry, because let me tell you, I have had a day
好东西坏东西啊Perry，要知道我整天都在忙啊
Uh, it's a little girl?
呃，小女孩怎么算？
That would be bad
这算坏东西嘛
Ruby's scythe
Ruby的镰刀
Oh, no
噢，不
Do you think she fell?
你觉得她掉下去了？
Fell?
掉下去？
Down there
从那里
Oh, why
噢，天哪
Of course..
对啊..
Of course, of course, of course!
对啊，对啊，对啊！
What is it?
怎么了？
How could I be so stupid?
我怎么这么傻？
Dr. Oobleck, what's wrong?
Oobleck博士，到底怎么了？
Mountain Glenn!
幽谷山脉！
Yes, an expansion of Vale that was inevitably destroyed by creatures of Grimm
没错，是个最终被戮兽摧毁的溪谷扩张地
Previously home to thousands of people
而之前居民有好几千
Working people commuting to the city, the main city
上下班的人来往于主城之间
Developed a subway system to the inner city
开发了地铁系统通往内城区
Grimm attacks increased, population endangered, now desperately searching for shelter
戮兽袭击越来越频繁，全民危机，他们绝望地寻求庇护所
City evacuates into the metro tunnels and what did they find?
全城避难到地铁隧道，猜猜他们发现了什么？
The southeast quadrant of Vale is known for wild forests and deep caves!
溪谷东南区以大片的原始森林和幽深的洞穴闻名！
Doc, what are you saying?
博士，你在说什么？
My dear, we're not just looking for an underground crime network
亲爱的，我们找的不仅仅是个地下犯罪网
We're looking for an 'underground' crime network!
他们真的在地下啊！
They've been working in caves?
他们在洞里干活？
No, no, Mountain Glenn was Vale's first serious attempt at expansion
不不，溪谷第一次正式扩张就在幽谷山脉
It worked for a short period of time, thanks to an aggressive perimeter defense
能取得短暂成功多亏了主动边界防御手段
And unique transportation
及独特的运输手段
The city developed an elaborate subway system
城市精心打造了一套地铁系统
to carry citizens safely from the new territory into the main Kingdom
用来把新领地的居民安全带回王国内部
Sadly, without the many natural barriers Vale had to protect its borders
可惜的是，没有溪谷那种保卫边境的天然屏障
Mountain Glenn was doomed from the start
幽谷从一开始就注定要覆灭
As the end drew near, the citizens of the territory made one last attempt to survival
灭亡一步步逼近，居民们做出了最后挣扎来求生
They took up shelter beneath the city
他们在城市下面避难
In massive caves that they had cleared out for the subway
在建地铁时清空的大型洞穴里
And they had cut themselves off from the surface
然后切断了与地面的联系
An underground village?
一个地下城？
In a matter of speaking, yes, a safe haven
某种程度来说，没错，一个安全避难所
Until..
直到..
An explosion opened the mouth of another cavern
一次爆炸打开了另一个洞口
filled with subterranean Grimm
里头全是地底戮兽
After that, the Kingdom officially sealed off the tunnels
之后，王国正式封锁了隧道
creating the world's largest tomb
制造了世上最大的墓地
If Ruby is down there
如果Ruby在下面
We must find her
必须找到她
BRB
BRB
This SUB is presented by Baidu RWBY Bar Creator: sbz_kid
本字幕由百度RWBY吧提供 片源/翻译/时间轴/特效/后期：sbz_kid